<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task
  PUBLIC '-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN'
  'dtd1.2/technicalContent/dtd/task.dtd'>
<!-- This file is part of the DITA Open Toolkit project hosted on 
     Sourceforge.net. See the accompanying license.txt file for 
     applicable licenses.-->
<!-- (C) Copyright IBM Corporation 2001, 2005. All Rights Reserved.
 *-->
<task id="proptemplate" product="proposalresponse" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Creating Your Proposal Template</title>
  <shortdesc>a step-by-step guide to moving RFP content into a workable Word response</shortdesc>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>Breaking down your RFP will help you form your response. Always follow RFP explicit structure rules first, and default to RFP internal structure when no rule applies. </p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <stepsection>To break down your RFP or RFI:</stepsection>
      <step>
        <cmd>Identify submittal requirements</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Identify compliance guidelines</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Identify requirement questions for response</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Identify styling and formatting requirements</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Identify and save all evaluation criteria</cmd>
        <stepresult>Once done, you have all the pieces needed to create a compliant, responsive proposal response skeleton.</stepresult>
      </step>
     
      <stepsection>To build your response template</stepsection>
      <step>
        <cmd>Create a cover page and include all information requested in the RFP submittal requirements</cmd>
        <substeps>
          <substep>
            <cmd>Typical information includes: Title, RFP Number, Government Contact, Vendor
              Contact</cmd>
          </substep>
          <substep>
            <cmd/>
          </substep>
        </substeps>
      </step>
        
      <step>
        <cmd> Using the format of the original RFP, paste in any and all requirements to which the
          vendor will respond. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Using the styling and formatting requirements, create a style guide in Word to keep
          your document consistent. </cmd>
        <substeps>
          <substep>
            <cmd>You can also use their formatting rules and the text of their RFP to begin creating
              your Wall of Truth. Please refer to the Wall of Truth page for more information on how
              to use this tool.</cmd>
            <stepresult>By mimicking the style of the RFP itself, the vendor is more likely to
              complete a compliant proposal. A rule of thumb in proposal management is "give them
              back their own words." That is, when in doubt, use the wording or style of the RFP in
              your response. </stepresult>
          </substep>
        </substeps>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Identify sections of the RFP and assign them to your team members for content input</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <link format="dita" href="concept-example.xml" type="concept"/>
    <link format="dita" href="reference-example.xml" type="concept"/>
  </related-links>
</task>
